Guide to the Robert Dudley French Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert Dudley French papers
1857-1987
1921-1954
MS 1264
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
Correspondence, writings, research notes, teaching materials, printed matter, a diary, a scrapbook, and photographs (1922-1952) comprise the papers. The teaching materials and the research notes reflect French's interest in Chaucer. A portion of the correspondence concerns Memorial Quadrangle at Yale, about which he published a book in 1929. There is also a substantial number of letters from students at Jonathan Edwards College, of which he was master from 1930 to 1953. Other correspondents are Robert Bates, John Philip Marchant and Emerson Tuttle.
French, Robert Dudley, 1888-1954
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dwight Blakeslee, 1981; gift of Bernard Lytton, 2001.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Dudley French (1888-1954): professor of English; A.B., Yale, 1910, A.M., 1914, Ph.D., 1920; instructor in English, Yale, 1914-1919, assistant professor, 1919-1926, associate professor, 1926-1930, professor and master of Jonathan Edwards College, 1930-1953.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, research notes, teaching materials, printed matter, a diary, a scrapbook, and photographs (1922-1952) comprise the papers. The teaching materials and the research notes reflect French's interest in Chaucer. A portion of the correspondence concerns Memorial Quadrangle at Yale, about which he published a book in 1929. There is also a substantial number of letters from students at Jonathan Edwards College, of which he was master from 1930 to 1953. Other correspondents are Robert Bates, John Philip Marchant and Emerson Tuttle.
Memorial Quadrangle (Yale University); Diaries; Scrapbooks; Educators; Bates, Robert Chapman, 1901-1942; Chaucer, Geoffrey, -1400; French, Robert Dudley, 1888-1954; Marchant, John Philip; Tuttle, H. E. (Henry Emerson), 1890-1946; Jonathan Edwards College (Yale University); Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of English
- Inventory, 1857-1955; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Preliminary Inventory by Tina Fagas, 1981 Apr
  Received from: Dwight Blakesee, 1981 Jul 14
  - Correspondence, 1929-1930, 1936, 1938, 1950, undated
    - Bates, Robert, undated (Box 1)
    - Jonathan Edwards students, 1943-1951, undated (Box 1)
    - Lowell Lectures, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Marchant, John Philip, 1940-1945 (Box 1)
    - Memorial Quadrangle, 1921-1930, undated (Box 1)
    - Personal-Retirement, 1946-1954 (Box 1)
    - Tuttle, Emerson, 1944 (Box 1)
    - Emerson Tuttle Memorial, 1946 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Writings, Lectures and Research Materials
    - House of Fame, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
    - Bibliographies, Course Materials, 1930-1936, undated (Box 1)
    - Lowell Lectures, 1937 (Box 1)
    - English 112, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
    - Chaucer: Miscellaneous Notes, 1939-1940, 1946 (Box 1)
    - English 31, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - English II: Chaucer, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
    - English 30a, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
    - English 30 and 31 [11 folders], 1944-1952 (Box 1)
    - Lecture Notes, 1950 (Box 1)
    - English 30 [2 folders], 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - The Diary of a Wandering Philosopher, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Canturbury Tales, Croft Classics Text Collection, undated (Box 1)
    - Canturbury Tales, Framing, undated (Box 1)
    - Chaucer: For Investigation, undated (Box 1)
    - Chaucer: Pronounciation, undated (Box 1)
    - Curtis, J.T., [ed.] The Vision of Piers Plowman, undated (Box 1)
    - English 30, undated (Box 1)
    - Lectures on Sundry Occasions, undated (Box 1)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 1)
    - Notes on the Jacobite Journal, undated (Box 1)
    - Passus VI [2 folders], undated (Box 1)
    - St. Thomas: Summa Cantro Gentiles, undated (Box 1)
    - Somnocasia or The House of Sleep, undated (Box 1)
    - Troilus and Criseyde, undated (Box 1)
    - W.L.H. # 107, undated (Box 1)
    - Work in Progress, undated (Box 1)
    - Writings by others, 1928, undated (Box 1)
  - Class lists of Jonathan Edwards, 1953-1955 (Box 1)
  - Estate of Patricia C. Means, 1937-1941 (Box 1)
  - Material relating to Avon Old Farms, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Drawings, undated (Box 1)
  - Osborn, R.C., Drawings, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
  - Printed Matter
    - College Plan, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1929-1946, undated (Box 1)
    - Memorabilia, 1930-1946 (Box 1)
    - Birth and Wedding Announcements of Jonathan Edwards Students, 1948-1950, undated (Box 1)
    - Chaucer: Equatorie of the Planets, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Chaucer: Research Report No. 14 Committee on Research and Bibliography of the Chaucer Group of the Modern Language Association of America, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Diary, [undated] (Box 1)
    - Retirement, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Obituaries, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1857-1910 (Box 2)
  - Photographs [4 folders], 1922-1952, undated (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession 2002-M-035
  - Correspondence
    - Family, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Curtis, Edward Ely, 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Goldberger, Paul, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Menner, Robert J., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Retirement [Congratulatory letters, clippings], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1946, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - White, Helen, 1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified, 1926-1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Humor, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs [Jonathan Edwards College], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Writings of others, 1928, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)